A Guide to the Brewer Family Genealogical Notes, ca. 1986-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Brewer Family Genealogical Notes, ca. 1986-1997
The Library of Virginia
42634
3.6 cu. ft. (7 boxes)
Marvin T. Broyhill III
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marvin T. Broyhill III, April 2006.
Scope and Content
Includes information on the descendants of John Brewer (d. 1635) of Warwick County, Virginia, by way of London, England, including information on lines which settled in Brunswick County, Charles City County, Isle of Wight County, Nansemond County, and Northumberland County; and Arkansas, Alabama, Georgia, Kentucky, Maryland, North Carolina, Ohio, and Tennessee. Other surnames mentioned: Broyhill, Burwell, Duncan, Earp, Hensley, Holliday, Selden, and Souder. Collection includes correspondence, deeds, genealogical and ancestral charts, marriage records, newspaper clippings, tax lists, and wills relating to the Brewer family and associated families. Also includes research notes and drafts of several works by Marvin T. Broyhill, including The Brewer Families of Colonial Virginia.
Contents List
- A Teacher's Guide to the Industrial Revolution, Marvin T. Broyhill, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Advertisements, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alabama, 1798-1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alvin Reynolds, 1629-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ambrose Brewer and John Greene, 1854-1855 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Ambrose Brewer Family, 1753-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Appomattox Iron Works Historic Preservation Project, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Arkansas, 1836-1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Aubrey Stark, 1740-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Barnaby, 1798-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Brewer: Allegra Research, 1631-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brewer, Asa, ca. 1730-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Brewer, Ben Letters, 1748-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Brewer, Books on, ca. 1610-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Brewer, Brunswick County, VA, 1751-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Brewer-Byers Research, ca. 1548-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Brewer, Chris, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Brewer-Congelton Papers, 1540-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Brewer Correspondence, 1669-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Brewer Families of Colonial Virginia, Supporting Documentation Part I, Marvin T. Broyhill, 1626-1776 and 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Brewer Families of Colonial Virginia, Supporting Documentation Part II, Marvin T. Broyhill, 1626-1776 and 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Brewer-Hensley Ancestral Chart, 1745-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Brewer, Ind. and Ill., 1645-1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Brewer, John of Stanley Hund., 1623-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Brewer Marriages N.C., ca. 1780-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Brewer, Mississippi, 1820-1840 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Brewer, Mrs. Paula Anthony, 1619-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Brewer Records (First Edition), ca. 1622-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Brewer-Related Families-Holliday, Burwell, 1608-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Brewer Researcher Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Brewer, Wilkes County, N.C., 1780-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Broyhill Family Album, American Genealogies, Inc., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Brunswick Tax List, 1760 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Bush, ca. 1600-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Cameron, 1776-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Chatham Co., N.C., 1769-1915 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Cook, 1739-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Dixon, 1744-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Doris Stone, 1632-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Duncan Family History, 1613-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Early Development of the Steam Engine, Marvin T. Broyhill, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Earp Family, ca. 1650-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Earp Family, 1650-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Elizabeth Allergue, ca. 1770-1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- England, 1554-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Family, ca. 1600-1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Fred Dorman, 1720-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Genealogical Helper, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Genealogists-Misc. Correspondence, 1636-1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Georgia, 1756-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Greensville County Records, 1783-1799 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Haskett, Jean, 1670-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Hoard, 1814-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Hooper, 1744-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Invoices, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- J. Reddin Research, 1743-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Joe Brewer Misc., 1622-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- John Brewer (1595-1621) Line and Related Families, ca. 1574-1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- John Brewer of Northampton Co., Virginia, 1680-1710 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Johnson, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Jones, ca. 1565-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Kentucky, 1642-1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- L.D. Brewer, ca. 1574-1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Linneman, 1744-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Mae Stevenson, 1671-1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Mary Cary, 1642-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Maryland, ca. 1634-1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Military Records, 1722-1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, ca. 1548-1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous Pedigree Charts, 1586-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Misc. Virginia Records, 1804-1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Moore County, N.C., 1754-1819 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Moody, 1824-1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Mrs. William, Gen., 1648-1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Name Index for The Brewer Families of Colonial Virginia, Marvin T. Broyhill, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Nansemond, 1702-1866 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1868 and undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- No Reply, 1740-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Ohio, 1770-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Peterson, 1796-1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Princess Anne County Records, 1735-1850 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Purvis, 1678-1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Report- Brewer of Colonial Virginia, 1627-1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Research Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Rhea Netherland, 1830-1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Roberts, ca. 1695-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Sanborn Insurance Maps Relating to the Appomattox Iron Works, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Seldens of Virginia, 1614-1910 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Souder, 1631-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Souder Genealogical Chart, 1769-1926 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Southampton County Records, 1750-1875 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Splawn, 1862-1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Tennessee, 1790-1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Tenn.-McClung Collection, 1565-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Texas, 1746-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Virginia Genealogical Publications, ca. 1600-1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Whitchurch, a Short History, R. B. James, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Working Notes, Brewer Families of Colonial Virginia, 1626-1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)